

Springfield. Massachusetts

[ (413) 472-9082 | ■ julioapaton@gmail.com

# Summary.

C++ Senior Software Engineer with 8+ years experience, has led teams to deliver critical applications in international defense programs. Motivated to continue to learn and grow as a professional and to help other team members to achieve their full potential. A Spaniard recently moved to the United States looking forward to making his first contribution.

# Work Experience

### **Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)**

Valdepeñas, Spain Apr. 2021 - Present

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

· Mentoring new members of the team.

- · Remote communication with the client for requirement specification and support.
- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link solution software.
- In-depth use of modern C++, STL, Boost, TCP/IP communications and multi-threading.

#### **Tecnobit S.L.U. (Optronic Systems)**

Valdepeñas, Spain

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 21

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Use of bug finding tools such as AddressSanitizer and Valgrind.
- Embedded software design and development in C/C++.
- Remote and on-site support to client.
- · CI of SW components.
- Technologies used include C++14, Xilinx SDK, Yocto Project and Jenkins.

### **Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)**

Valdepeñas, Spain

Jan. 2018 - Dec. 2019

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Plan, organize and monitor tasks of the software development team.
- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link solution software.
- · Integration of communications systems such as network controller, modem, radio, GPS, NTP server, radar and cryptographic device.
- · On-site system deployment, testing, support and training for Bangladesh navy on ships, ground stations and aircrafts.
- In-depth use of C++, STL, Boost, TCP/IP communications and multi-threading.

### **Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)**

Valdepeñas, Spain

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jun. 2014 - Dec. 2017

- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link Systems including Link11, Link16, Link22, JREAP and SIMPLE protocols.
- Port a VxWorks Tactical Data Link processor application to Linux.
- Technologies used include C++11 and Qt.

## **VISILAB Research Group (UCLM)**

Valdepeñas, Spain Sep. 2012 - May. 2014

• Design and develop computer vision applications for desktop, Android and iOS platforms using OpenCV.

- [Book] OpenCV Essentials, Packt Publishing, 2014.
- [Article] A Vision-Based Localization Algorithm for an Indoor Navigation App, Eighth International Conference on Next Generation Mobile Apps, Services and Technologies (NGMAST), 2014.

# Education

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

## **Expert in Video Games Development**

Ciudad Real, Spain

UCLM (University of Castilla - La Mancha)

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2014

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering
UCLM (UNIVERSITY OF CASTILLA - LA MANCHA)

Ciudad Real, Spain Sep. 2011 - Jun. 2013

OCEM (ONIVERSITY OF CHOTIEST EXTINATED)

**Erasmus Scholarship** 

Eindhoven, The Netherlands

TUE(EINDHOVEN UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY)

Sep. 2009 - Jul. 2010

**Technical Engineering in Computer Systems** 

Ciudad Real, Spain

UCLM(University of Castilla - La Mancha)

Sep. 2007 - Jun. 2011

DECEMBER 1, 2022 JULIO PATON · RÉSUMÉ